Inventory of the Philip Sidney Van Cise papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Philip Sidney Van Cise papers
1917-1919
40003
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Letters, clippings, and miscellanea, relating to activities of the American Expeditionary Forces in France during World War I.
Van Cise, Philip Sidney, 1884-.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1940.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1884 October 25 Born, Deadwood, South Dakota
1907 Graduates from University of Colorado
1917-1919 Assistant chief of staff for intelligence, 81st Division
circa 1919-1942 Lieutenant colonel, United States Army
1969 December 8 Died, Denver, Colorado
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is comprised of letters, clippings, and miscellanea, relating to activities of the American Expeditionary Forces in France during World War I. Correspondence from Van Cise to his parents is included in the collection and reflects his experiences during the war. Also included in the collection are samples of insignia from the 81st Infantry Division, also known as the Wildcats.
United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; United States. Army. Infantry Division, 81st.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--France.
- Correspondence
  - 1917 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - 1918 January (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - 1918 February (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 1918 March (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - 1918 April (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Correspondence from France, 1918-1919
    - 1918 May (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1918 June (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1918 July (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - 1918 August (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - 1918 September (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - 1918 October (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - 1918 November (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - 1918 December (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - 1919 January (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - 1919 February (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - 1919 March (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - 1919 April (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - 1919 May (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - 1919 June (Box-folder 1: 19)
- Maps of the United States and Europe, undated (Box-folder 1: 20)
- Newspaper clippings about the war and about Van Cise, circa 1918 (Box-folder 1: 21)
- Military record, 1922, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 22)
- Postcards, letters, and booklets, circa 1918 (Box-folder 1: 23)
- Military insignia, undated (Box-folder 1: 24)